Guide to the Sylvester Nemes Papers1973-2010
Montana State University Library, Archives and Special Collections, Manuscript Collections
Sylvester Nemes Papers
1973-2010
Montana State University Library, Archives and Special Collections, Manuscript Collections
2576
15 linear feet 35 boxes
The Sylvester Nemes Papers consists of research, notes, drafts and manuscripts of Nemes' books, both his published works on fly fishing, as well as two unpublished works of historical fiction. Also included in the collection are correspondence, a brief biography, miscellaneous personal records, his obituary, business and professional records, photographs, negatives, memorabilia, and slides.
This collection is open for research.
Research papers, publication documents, correspondence, and photographs created or collected by Sylvester Nemes were purchased by Montana State University from Hazel Nemes, Bozeman, Montana, on October 3, 2011.
Series 1 Biographical material
Series 2 Business and Professional Records
Series 3 Correspondence
Series 4 Book Manuscripts, Drafts, and Book-Specific Research
Series 5 General Research and Notes
Series 6 Photographs, Slides, and Memorabilia
Sylvester Nemes was born on April 2, 1922 in Erie, Pennsylvania. His parents, Dominic Nemes and Pauline Angel, were Romanian. He grew up in Cleveland, Ohio, where he was introduced to fly tying by a friend and mentor, and traveled frequently to Pennsylvania with his homemade flies to fish the rivers and streams there. Nemes enlisted in the Army at age 19 as the U.S. was entering World War II. He was stationed at the Ibsley Air Field in Hampshire, England as a member of the Fighter Control Squadron with the Eighth Air Force. While stationed, he was set up on a blind date with Hazel Mary Barclay, an English nursing student. Nemes landed at Omaha Beach on D-Day, staying there for nine months as part of a team directing fighter aircraft. When he returned to England, he married Hazel on March 17, 1945 in Southampton, Hampshire. After the war, Hazel and Sylvester's first child, Diana, was born in England. The family moved to the U.S. where their second and third children, Eric and Gregory, were born. While the couple raised their family, Nemes earned a bachelor's degree in English from Kent State University. He went on to work as a copy writer and a photographer in Cleveland, Detroit, and Chicago. Nemes, Hazel, and their children moved to Crown Point, Indiana in 1961, where Nemes worked as a photojournalist and continued to cultivate his love of fly fishing.
Nemes published his first book in 1975 through Chatham Press. The Soft-Hackled Fly championed wet fly fishing and the beauty and utility of flies tied with bird feathers in an era when dry fly fishing was the dominant trend. In the book he details the history of the soft-hackled fly and gives instruction on tying them and using them in fishing. Nemes went on to become a prolific author on the subject of fly fishing, writing Learn How to Fly Fish in One Day (1986), Soft-Hackled Imitations (1991), The Soft-Hackled Fly: A Trout Fisherman's Guide (1993), The Soft-Hackled Fly Addict (1993), Spinners (1995), Six Months in Scotland: an American View of its Salmon Fishing (1998), Two Centuries of Soft-Hackled Flies: a Survey of the Literature With Original Patterns, 1747-Present (2004), and The Soft-Hackled Fly and Tiny Soft Hackles: a Trout Fisherman's Guide (2006). He wrote two unpublished novels: "Goodbye, Crown Point," about John Dillinger, the Depression-era bank robber, and an unnamed manuscript about World War II-era P38 fighter aircraft pilots. Hazel and Sylvester moved to San Francisco in the early eighties before settling in Bozeman, Montana, at the base of the Bridger Mountains, in 1984. Nemes continued to fish, create his own fly patterns, and write books. He had admirers as far-flung as Japan, where fans of his started a fly fishing club devoted to the use of the soft hackle, and a Nemes-branded fly fishing rod was produced and sold. He was honored by Trout Unlimited in Bozeman in 2008 with their Legends of the Headwaters award. Nemes died at home on February 3, 2011 outside of Bozeman.
The Sylvester Nemes Papers primarily contain research, notes, drafts and manuscripts of Nemes's books, both his published works on fly fishing, as well as two unpublished works of historical fiction. His research materials include typed pages and handwritten notes in spiral-bound notebooks, as well as galley proofs and artwork. The collection also contains a large amount of correspondence from readers and fans who expressed the admiration for Nemes's work, and submitted orders for his books and hand-tied flies. A small amount of biographical material is also included in the collection, and includes family correspondence, a brief biography, miscellaneous personal records, and his obituary. Nemes's business and professional records mostly consist of correspondence with publishers, book and fly orders and invoices, and other records related to the writing and publishing of his books. In the final series there are photographs, negatives, memorabilia, and several binders of slides taken by Nemes of flies, landscapes in the West and in England and Scotland, fish and rivers, and friends and family.
Nemes, Sylvester--Archives
Scotland--Description and travel; England--Description and travel; West (U.S.)--Description and travel; Bozeman (Mont.); England; Montana; Montana--Bozeman; Scotland; United States; United States, West
Americans--England; Fishers--Montana; Fly fishing; Fly tyers--Montana; Fly tying; Publishers and publishing--United States; World War, 1939-1945--Aerial operations, American--Fiction; Americans; Fishers; Fly fishing; Fly tyers; Fly tying; Military operations, Aerial--American; Publishers and Publishing; Travel; World War (1939-1945)
Fishing and Canning; Military; Publishers and Publishing; Sports and Recreation; Montana; Bozeman; Photographs
Photographs; Personal papers--Montana--Bozeman; Archives; Fiction
- Biographical material, 1
  Nemes's biographical materials include a small assortment of personal items and descriptions of his life. They include a portrait of Nemes, family correspondence, a short biographical sketch written in the mid-1980s, and his obituary from the Bozeman Daily Chronicle. Miscellaneous personal records consist of an international driver's license, receipts, and loan paperwork from the 1990s.
  - Nemes Portrait, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Biography, 1980s-2011 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, undated; 1995; 1997 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Personal Records, 1992-2001 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Business and Professional Records, 2
  Nemes's professional records document his publishing career and related business ventures. Records associated with his publications are most prominent and include wholesale book orders, royalty reports, receipts from travels to Europe, publisher correspondence with Stackpole Books and Chatham Press, book publicity materials, and articles written by and about Nemes. His business records also feature legal agreements, including an agreement to produce a Nemes-branded fishing rod in Japan.
  - Awards/Certificates, 1990-2007 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Organizations, 1981-2009 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Articles by Nemes, 1975; undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Articles about Nemes, 1982-2011 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Book Reviews/Press, 1986-1996 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Book Publicity, 1988-1989; 1995 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Book Publicity Mailings, 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Book/Fly Orders, 1981-2002 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - The Soft Hackled Fly Orders from Magazine Ad (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - The Soft Hackled Fly Orders from Magazine Ad (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Fly Fishing Heritage, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Fly Fisherman's Library, 1982; undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Fly Fisherman Magazine, 1975-1983 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Fly Fisherman Japan Edition, 1983; undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - English Correspondence/Research, 1974-1982; undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Trip to England/Fishing in England, 1972-1986; undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Trip to Scotland, 1996-1997; undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Stackpole Books - Correspondence, 1984-2006 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Stackpole Books - Correspondence, 1984-2006 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Stackpole Books - Royalty Statements, Invoices, 1986-2007 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - General Publisher Correspondence, 1973-2005 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Publishing Agreements, 1985-2010; undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Title Page Proofs, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Submission to Barnes and Noble, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - English Publisher Correspondence, 1995-1996 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Chatham Press, 1975-1981 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Chatham Press, 1975-1980 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Goodbye Crown Point - Publisher Search, 1992-2007 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Publisher Price Quotes, 1982-1995 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous Invoices/Receipts (Incoming), 1983-1996 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Nemes-Branded Japanese Rod, 1997-2000 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Modern Imaging Dispute, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Copyright Registration, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Color World Printers, 1988-1998 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Umpqua Feather Merchants, 1990-2002 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Transcribed Tapes, 1975; 1977 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Brochures and Catalogs, 1990-2002 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Fly Fishing Dictionary, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Business Correspondence, 1980-1989; undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - General Articles and Newspaper Clippings, 1993-2006; undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous Business Records (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Spinners - Trademark (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, 3; Series 3
  Nemes's correspondence contains incoming and outgoing letters related to his publications. The bulk of the correspondence consists of letters to Nemes from his readers, including fan mail, book and fly orders, and questions seeking fishing advice. Some letter writers sent Nemes examples of their hand-crafted flies in addition to their letters. The flies are filed separately and can be found among his collected memorabilia. A small amount of outgoing correspondence contains copies of letters written by Nemes between 1973 and 2008 and relates to his publications and fly and book orders.
  - A (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - A (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - B (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - B (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - B (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - B (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - B (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - B (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - C (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - C (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - C (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - C (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - D (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - D (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - E (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - F (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - F (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - G (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - G (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - H (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - H (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - H (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - H (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - H (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - I (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - J (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - K (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - K (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - K (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - L (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - L (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - L (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - M (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - M (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - M (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - M (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - N (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - O (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - P (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - P (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - P (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Q (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - R (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - R (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - R (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - S (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - S (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - S (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - S (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - T (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - T (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - U (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - V (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - W (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - W (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Y (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Z (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - No Last Name (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - No Last Name (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Letter Fragments (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Outgoing
  - 1973-1975 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - 1976 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - 1977 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - 1980-1989 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - 1990-1994 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - 1995-1999 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - 2000-2008 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - undated (Box 13, Folder 8)
- Book Manuscripts, Drafts, and Book-Specific Research, 4; Series 4
  Nemes's book manuscripts, drafts, and book-specific research features pre-publication copies of his books on fly fishing and his non-fiction writings. This series contains drafts, manuscripts, galleys, artwork, notes, and collected articles for his books. Of greatest significance is an early draft (circa 1973) of his most famous book, The Soft-Hackled Fly.
  - Soft Hackled Fly Manuscript (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Soft Hackled Fly Manuscript (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Soft Hackled Fly Manuscript (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Soft Hackled Fly Manuscript (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Soft Hackled Fly Manuscript (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Soft Hackled Fly Manuscript (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Soft Hackled Fly Manuscript (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Soft Hackled Fly Manuscript (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Soft Hackled Fly Manuscript (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Soft Hackled Fly - Title Page (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Soft Hackled Fly - Intro to New Edition (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Soft Hackled Fly - Folder Notes (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Learn How to Fly Fish - Drafts (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Learn How to Fly Fish - Drafts (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Learn How to Fly Fish - Artwork (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Learn How to Fly Fish - Artwork (Box 14, Folder 16)
    [see box 32]
  - Learn How to Fly Fish - Drafts (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Learn How to Fly Fish - Artwork (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Soft Hackled Fly Imitations - Handwritten Notes (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Soft Hackled Fly Imitations - Notes (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Soft Hackled Fly Imitations - Drafts (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Soft Hackled Fly Imitations - Drafts (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Soft Hackled Fly Imitations - Drafts (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Soft Hackled Fly Imitations - Drafts (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Soft Hackled Fly Imitations - Drafts (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Soft Hackled Fly Imitations - Drafts (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Soft Hackled Fly Imitations - Drafts (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Soft Hackled Fly Imitations - Artwork (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Soft Hackled Fly Imitations - Manuscript (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Soft Hackled Fly Imitations - Manuscript (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Soft Hackled Fly Imitations - Manuscript (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - D. Hughes Soft Hackled Fly Imitations Introduction (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Soft Hackled Fly Imitations - Artwork (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Soft Hackled Fly Imitations - Galleys (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Soft Hackled Fly Imitations - Galleys (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Soft Hackled Fly Imitations - Galleys (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Spinners - Book Proposal (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Spinners - Notes (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Spinners - Drafts (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Spinners - Drafts (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Spinners - Drafts (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Spinners - Drafts (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Spinners - Drafts (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Spinners - Drafts (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Spinners - Drafts (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Spinners - Drafts (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Spinners - Drafts (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Spinners - Drafts (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Spinners - Drafts (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Spinners - Drafts (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Spinners - Drafts (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Spinners - Drafts (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Spinners - Artwork (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Scotland Travel (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Scotland Travel (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Scotland Travel (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Scotland Articles and Research (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Scotland Articles and Research (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Scotland Articles and Research (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Scotland Articles and Research (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - United Kingdom Articles and Newspaper Clippings (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Six Months in Scotland - Chapter Ideas (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Six Months in Scotland - Drafts (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Six Months in Scotland - Drafts (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Six Months in Scotland - Drafts (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Six Months in Scotland - Drafts (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Six Months in Scotland - Drafts (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Six Months in Scotland - Drafts (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Six Months in Scotland - Drafts (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Six Months in Scotland (?) - Drafts (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Six Months in Scotland - Artwork (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Two Centuries of Soft Hackled Flies - Handwritten Notes (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Two Centuries of Soft Hackled Flies - Articles (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Two Centuries of Soft Hackled Flies - Articles (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Two Centuries of Soft Hackled Flies - Articles (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Two Centuries of Soft Hackled Flies - Articles (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Two Centuries of Soft hackled Flies - Articles (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Two Centuries of Soft Hackled Flies - Articles (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Two Centuries of Soft Hackled Flies - Manuscript (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Two Centuries of Soft Hackled Flies - Manuscript (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Two Centuries of Soft Hackled Flies - Manuscript (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Two Centuries of Soft Hackled Flies - Manuscript (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Two Centuries of Soft Hackled Flies - Manuscript (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Two Centuries of Soft Hackled Flies - Manuscript (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Two Centuries of Soft Hackled Flies - Manuscript (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Two Centuries of Soft Hackled Flies - Manuscript (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Two Centuries of Soft Hackled Flies - Galleys (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Two Centuries of Soft Hackled Flies - Galleys (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Two Centuries of Soft Hackled Flies - Galleys (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Tiny Soft Hackles - Notebooks (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Tiny Soft Hackles - Research (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Tiny Soft Hackles - Manuscript (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Tiny Soft Hackles - Manuscript (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - P38 Novel - Notes (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - P38 Novel - Notes (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - P38 Novel - Articles and Research (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - P38 Novel - Articles and Research (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - P38 Novel - Articles and Research (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - P38 Novel - Articles and Research (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - P38 Novel - Drafts (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - P38 Novel - Manuscript (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Goodbye, Crown Point - Dillinger Articles (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Goodbye, Crown Point - Dillinger Articles (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Goodbye, Crown Point - Dillinger Articles (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Goodbye, Crown Point - Dillinger Articles (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Goodbye, Crown Point - Dillinger Articles (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Goodbye, Crown Point - Dillinger Articles (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Goodbye, Crown Point - Dillinger Articles (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Goodbye, Crown Point - Dillinger Articles (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Goodbye, Crown Point - Dillinger Articles (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Goodbye, Crown Point - Dillinger Articles (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Goodbye, Crown Point - Dillinger Articles (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Goodbye, Crown Point - Notes (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Goodbye, Crown Point - Notes (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Goodbye, Crown Point - Manuscript (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Goodbye, Crown Point - Manuscript (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Goodbye, Crown Point - Manuscript (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Goodbye, Crown Point - Manuscript (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Goodbye, Crown Point - Manuscript (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Goodbye, Crown Point - Manuscript (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Goodbye, Crown Point - Manuscript (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Goodbye, Crown Point - Manuscript (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Goodbye, Crown Point - Manuscript (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Goodbye, Crown Point - Manuscript (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Goodbye, Crown Point - Manuscript (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Goodbye, Crown Point - Manuscript (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Goodbye, Crown Point - Manuscript (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Goodbye, Crown Point - Manuscript (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Goodbye, Crown Point - Manuscript (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Goodbye, Crown Point - Manuscript (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Goodbye, Crown Point - Manuscript (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Goodbye, Crown Point - Manuscript (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Goodbye, Crown Point - Manuscript (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Goodbye, Crown Point - Manuscript (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Goodbye, Crown Point - Manuscript (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Goodbye, Crown Point - Manuscript Sample (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Unidentified Manuscript - Soft Hackled Fly Origins/Tarpon Story (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Unidentified Manuscript - Fishing the Soft Hackled Fly (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Unidentified Manuscript - Fishing the Soft Hackled Fly in Big Rivers (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Unidentified Manuscript - Fishing Soft Hackles (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Unidentified Manuscript - Soft Hackled Fly Writing (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Unidentified Manuscript - Fiction Manuscript (Box 28, Folder 8)
- General Research and Notes, 5
  Nemes's general research and notes consist of handwritten notes and collected articles related to his writings. Notes include research, drafts, and edits of Nemes's books and articles. They also include handwritten book order information, remarks on fly tying, reminders, and stray thoughts. Notes are contained on loose papers, in spiral notebooks, and on legal pads. Several small memo pads also contain dated entries regarding fishing trips and document Nemes's fishing location, weather, and insect hatch descriptions. A small collection of articles on entomology and the history of elementary schools is also included among these materials.
  - Entomological Society of London Articles (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Entomology Articles (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Handwritten Notes (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Handwritten Notes (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Handwritten Notes (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Handwritten Notes (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Handwritten Notes (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Handwritten Notes (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Handwritten Notes (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Handwritten Notes (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Handwritten Notes (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Handwritten Notes (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Handwritten Notes (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Handwritten Notes (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Handwritten Notes (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Handwritten Notes (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Handwritten Notes (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Handwritten Notes (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Handwritten Notes (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Handwritten Notes (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Handwritten Notes (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Handwritten Notes (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Handwritten Notes (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Handwritten Notes (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Handwritten Notes (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Handwritten Notes (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - History of Elementary Schools - Articles (Box 32, Folder 6)
- Photographs, Slides, and Memorabilia, 6; Series 6
  Nemes's photographs, slides and memorabilia features visual materials related to his life and career. Photographs include color prints of Nemes with family and friends, readers' photos sent to Nemes, and 3x5 negatives of fly tying. The series also includes binders of slides featuring images of flies, rivers, the English and Scottish countryside, and western landscapes. Nemes used slides as visual aids at speaking engagements and the slides likely relate to publicity events for his books and other public appearances. There is a small collection of flies (mostly sent to Nemes by readers), his Legend of the Headwaters award, and a framed photo with mounted flies from a Japanese fishing club.
  - Photos: S. Nemes, #1-7 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Photos: S. Nemes and Others, #8-13 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Photos: Unidentified people, #14-17 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Photos: Miscellaneous fishing-related, #18-20 (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Photos: Normandy map, #21-24 (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Photos: Fly tying (Tying leader to fly, #25-27, Blood knot, #28-37), #25-37 (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - Negatives: Flies, #38-46 (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - Negatives: Fly tying, #47-69 (Box 32, Folder 14)
  - Negatives: Fishing/casting, #70-83 (Box 32, Folder 15)
  - Negatives: Horses, #84-85 (Box 32, Folder 16)
  - Photo: Federation of Fly Fishers Conclave, #86, August 1988 (Box 32, Folder 17)